<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://chhhris.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chhhris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-11T09:48:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://chhhris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A simple expanation of how the NSA program PRISM works]]></title>
    <link href="http://chhhris.github.io/blog/2013/06/11/a-simple-expanation-of-how-the-nsa-program-prism-works-or/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-11T08:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://chhhris.github.io/blog/2013/06/11/a-simple-expanation-of-how-the-nsa-program-prism-works-or</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Or, how the author of the infamous top-secret PPT presentation has clearly never seen the inside of a SQL table.</h2>

<p>When <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jun/07/prism-tech-giants-shock-nsa-data-mining">The Guardian</a> broke the story of the US Government&rsquo;s digital intelligence gathering operation (code named &ldquo;PRISM&rdquo;), the oft-quoted line from the Top Secret presentation an NSA analyst gave to his colleagues was that the NSA had &ldquo;direct access&rdquo; to the servers at Google, Microsoft, Facebook, Yahoo!, Apple, among others (with Dropbox &ldquo;coming soon&rdquo; and Twitter <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2013/06/feature-friday-standing-up-for-your-users.html">conspicuous by its absence</a>).</p>

<p>The response from these tech companies was swift and <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jun/07/prism-tech-giants-shock-nsa-data-mining">unequivocal</a>. Turns out the NSA doesn&rsquo;t actually tap directly into the servers at these companies; instead, it has computers on-site to which NSA analysts post queries. The NSA computers then download the relevant data.</p>

<p>The imprecision of the NSA&rsquo;s presentation is clearly, obviously due to the fact that the author has never performed a SQL JOIN on two tables in a database tables!</p>

<p>In short, the way the PRISM works is the NSA collects as much data &ndash; every Google search, email, FB post and Verizon phone call &ndash; it can get its hands on. The NSA then cross-references this huge mountain of data with lists of known or suspected terrorists, persons of interest, et al. In other words, the NSA data analysts perform an <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/10/a-visual-explanation-of-sql-joins.html">INNER JOIN</a> on the two tables!</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a neat visualizing from <a href="http://blog.seldomatt.com/blog/2012/10/17/about-sql-joins-the-3-ring-binder-model/">Seldom Matt</a>:</p>

<p><img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/1702c57a6fd3a1048d1ab062d2cff590/tumblr_mo8cqssYw01qd3p27o1_500.png" alt="Image of &quot;binder method&quot; for visualizing and inner join" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
